# **Azad Mamiyev**

# Android Developer

#### **Profile**

Android Developer with 5 years of experience developing, designing, and maintaining Android apps in multiple industries such as product tech companies, startups, and consulting agencies. I am experienced in delivering features via A/B Testing, building Bitrise pipelines, writing tests, refactoring, and optimizing existing code.

# **Professional Experience**

# Senior Software Engineer, Azercell &

Sep 2023 – present

Successfully managed the smooth migration of users to the newly separated application.

Baku, Azerbaijan

• Developing and integrating payment features.

# Mobile Platform Developer, Cookpad ⊘

Aug 2022 – Jul 2023

• Migrated a flow of onboarding screens from XML Views to Jetpack Compose.

Bristol, United Kingdom

- Worked on building, editing, and optimizing Bitrise pipelines
- Covered features with unit, integration, and E2E tests.
- Assisted iOS Engineers with migration to use generated paths using CreateAPI.
- Implemented enhancements to the media player, significantly improving the user experience.
- Managed the release process, ensuring timely deployment of updates and monitoring Crashlytics for real-time crash reporting.

#### **Android Developer,** ByAllMeans $\varnothing$

Aug 2020 – Jul 2022

• Developed chat-related features with reactions.

Prague, Czech Republic

- Actively participated in product management, design & QA team meetings.
- Implemented Google Play Billing Library.
- Maintained the existing project with improvements to user experience.

#### **Education**

MSc., Web & Software Engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

• Experienced in genetic algorithms and management information systems.

Prague, Czech Republic

• Well-versed in patterns, user interface design, and networking.

**BSc., Computer Science,** Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University

Sep 2015 – Jun 2019

• Gained experience working on group projects.

Baku, Azerbaijan

#### Skills

Kotlin, Swift, Java, Coroutines, Jetpack Compose, Kotlin/Compose Multiplatform, Networking, Modularisation, MVVM, MVI, Unit and UI Testing, Continuous Integration, Gradle, Figma

## **Personal Projects**

### **Habitube,** Movie Library App ∅

- Successfully facilitated seamless migration from legacy technologies (Java, RxJava, XML Views) to modern development technologies (Kotlin, Coroutines, Compose) for end users.
- Designed elegant and user-friendly interfaces using Figma.

#### Languages

English — Fluent | Azerbaijani — Native | Russian — Native | Turkish — Limited | Czech — Basic